<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Peter Boni]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-02T12:46:59+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.peterboni.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Boni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[People Based Working]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/06/01/people-based-working/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-01T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/06/01/people-based-working</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some companies have traditional work environments. When you come into work, you have an assigned desk. You are physically located with your team, which is located within that teams larger team, and so on. The company feels like it physically revolves around you. You are physically partitioned &amp; packed into a master seating plan, maintained &amp; controlled by The Collective of Master Seating Plan Controllers.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>There&rsquo;s an obvious &amp; defined order to it all. You know where you sit. You know your place, because its there, day after day. It doesn&rsquo;t move, even though your work &amp; the people who you work with does. You are the master of your own domain. It contains your stuff, your possessions. It has your personal touch. Outside battles &amp; war rage, but inside your domain its peaceful. You have focus because of consistency.</p>

<p>Some companies have non traditional work environments. One style is ABW &ndash; Activity Based Working. When you come into work, you don&rsquo;t have an assigned desk. You have a locker like you did in school that contains your work tools &amp; minimal possessions. Your first task for the day is to find a desk. This is more complicated than it sounds. What time did you get in? What activity are you doing today?</p>

<p>Teams migrate in packs. One lone wolf can disrupt the established base of a team, and set them on a random migration path, which in turn has a ripple effect in the office ecosystem across a floor, and into other floors. Overt (mostly silent) psychological wars are fought over areas by teams posturing, and positioning of physical objects like whiteboards, agile card walls, posters, or pictures. Some teams are firmly entrenched, and won&rsquo;t be moved, even by the occasional interloper.</p>

<p>Once you select a desk, if you don&rsquo;t immediately clean it, you&rsquo;re touching potentially multiple people&rsquo;s germs all over the desk, keyboard, mouse &amp; phone, and then yourself &ndash; your face, your food, and other people. This all takes time that&rsquo;s not spent working, which can be frustrating. Sometimes you think &ldquo;I sat here yesterday. Maybe I don&rsquo;t need to clean everything today.&rdquo; As you sit there in this foreign, sparse, sterile, non personal environment, the people around you may or may not be different from yesterday. It depends what the people who come in after you do. Where will they go when they come in? What complex logic (or not for that matter) will they follow to select their desk?</p>

<p>The environment is mostly not peaceful, or conducive to solitary productive thinking work. There&rsquo;s more noise. People are more chatty. It&rsquo;s harder to concentrate for lengthy periods at a time, even in so called designated quiet work styled areas. It&rsquo;s exhausting.</p>

<p>To an outsider ABW may appear as chaos. But to an insider, strange things happen in ABW. You can sit next to people you are working with &amp; collaborate with them more effectively. You can sit next to different people. You can move if you don&rsquo;t want to sit next to someone. You can have random conversations that may, or may not prove immediately useful. The amazing thing is that you can do these things every day.</p>

<p>If you want to move to your activity there is no lengthy process through The Collective of Master Seating Plan Controllers. You just &hellip; move. You feel like you are part of something bigger than just your small team. You feel more empowered. You seem to physically revolve around the company with people, and the company &amp; the people feel like the core purpose of why you are there.</p>

<p>You learn to live with the noise, the constant interruptions, and not owning a space. The space serves a purpose, not just you. You begin to see patterns of movement &amp; highly productive collaboration. You start to participate &amp; change your style of working. You begin to think that you can&rsquo;t go back to a traditional work environment.</p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/26774102">Simon Sinek: If You Don&rsquo;t Understand People, You Don&rsquo;t Understand Business</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Is Water]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/05/11/this-is-water/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-11T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/05/11/this-is-water</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently took a month leave from work &amp; did absolutely nothing. Well not nothing. I did something I&rsquo;ve never done before. I didn&rsquo;t do any work. I spent it with my family. I relaxed. Really relaxed. I disconnected from my life of work, more work, the Internet, computers &amp; technology. Well, ok, mostly for the last few. This may not seem momentous to you, but for me it was.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The last major break I had was when my son was born. My idea then of relaxing in between all the crying and sleepless nights was to learn the Android platform by creating an <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=au.com.bankwest.mobile&amp;hl=en">App</a>. The App was released August 2011. Now with an average rating of 3.8 out of 5 and over 80,000 installs it has been successful, even if I wasn&rsquo;t successful at relaxing.</p>

<p>When I returned to work I felt strange. The first few days I was wondering why I was there. What was I doing. What was my purpose. Why did I come here (other than the obvious reasons). I&rsquo;d look out the window and feel in my soul that I needed to return to the existence I had come from. I missed my pain in the butt kids. There was the usual jokes with family and friends. &ldquo;Hey, how&rsquo;s reality? Happy to be back at work? ;)&rdquo;, to which I replied jokingly &ldquo;Reality sucks!&rdquo;.</p>

<p>What I started to notice in the first few days was that I was relaxed at my core. I could think before speaking &amp; putting words out there, making sure they were positive and added value. It sharpened my focus. I no longer felt like a speeding train. I felt like I&rsquo;d slowed down inside, and was more effective for it.</p>

<p>A few more days passed, and it was the end of the first week. The feeling of strangeness was still there, but so too was the feeling of being relaxed at my core. I resolved to fight like hell to keep it. I started to change my habits. I made time for breakfast in the morning. I resolved not to rush. I made time for exercise; riding, running, walking &amp; started weights again after many years. I made time for my family. I made time for meditation. I&rsquo;ve made time for thinking, writing &amp; doing. There&rsquo;s only so many hours in a day, so I stopped doing things that didn&rsquo;t add value, and just added noise to my life. It&rsquo;s a liberating feeling.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s affected me in other ways too. I had one of my best runs in my first week back at work. Relaxed. Smooth. Good pace &amp; rhythm. But still competitive. I still increased my pace, clawing at the road, gasping for breath for the last couple hundred metres. A neighbour would have seen this person run up the road, collapse on the lawn, gasping for breath, scrambling at his iPhone to press finish on Strava. As I lay there on the lawn, the beats from the earbuds combining with the pounding of my ears, sweat pouring off my face and down my neck, the wind hitting me, I felt alive. I felt great. It&rsquo;s reflected in my edited Strava Name for the run &ndash; &ldquo;BOOM FEEL MY RYTHM STICK BOUNCE !&rdquo;.</p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/65576562">This Is Water</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[App Dev is not Rapid]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/04/03/app-dev-is-not-rapid/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-03T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/04/03/app-dev-is-not-rapid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Application Development is not Rapid. There, I finally typed it. It feels like a weight off my fingers. I have been creating applications for over 20 years, and do a damn good job of it. I&rsquo;m not arrogant, there are many developers that are smarter, more creative, or more productive. If I was to describe myself as a developer in one word I&rsquo;d say simple, which is kind of funny, because fear of being labelled that has stopped me writing this in the past. This is a post based on my thoughts &amp; feelings at the state of application development.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I have written before about why I <a href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/24/creating-software/">create software</a>, and my struggle with software development complexity. I&rsquo;m going to tell a story about my experience with the Technology, and it&rsquo;s contribution to the People, Process &amp; Technology triad when building applications.</p>

<p>My first job out of university was doing Microsoft Access &lsquo;database&rsquo; development for a large mining company. I put database in quotes because I didn&rsquo;t think of Access as strictly a database at the time. We built tables with constraints &amp; relationships, queries, forms, reports, and logic (macros &amp; VBA). Mostly via point &amp; click, and writing simple code. We built applications. It was and still is amazing to me how much two Access developers built, with one of them being so naive &amp; inexperienced.</p>

<p>I then progressed to building a web application, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ColdFusion (version 4.0 from 1999) &amp; SQL Server. There&rsquo;s a few more technologies there than my Microsoft Access experience, but ColdFusion rocked. It joined the other technologies together seamlessly, and it made creating an application rapid. I felt productive.</p>

<blockquote><p>To me rapid development meant quickly building working application software that fulfilled a need with simple, powerful tools. It meant building &amp; joining together the parts in an easily learned, understood, and consistent way that supported change.</p></blockquote>

<p>Where did I find myself after a few experiences of rapid application development? I found myself in the distinctly non-rapid world of enterprise systems development. There was titanic Sun, IBM, Oracle &amp; Microsoft technologies. I found myself submerged in Sun Java, J2SE, J2EE, IBM WebSphere, Oracle Database, and Microsoft .NET &amp; Servers. Within each one I used a dizzying array of technologies &ndash; to use an abstract term to describe the things you could use &amp; the ways you could use them. There were plenty of acronyms that made you feel accomplished if you knew what they stood for, even if you didn&rsquo;t know what they did.</p>

<p>My view of web application architecture had exploded from a few technologies to many, many layers of them. ColdFusion was replaced by an astoundingly complex maze of choices. Want to display a database field on the screen? Oh, not so quick Mr Simple Developer. We need to do it in a modern, best practice, scalable way. I did not feel productive.</p>

<p>This is where some people would stop me in my story, call me a non-believer, and then begin to preach the virtues of their given religion. I have no desire to go into any of them here. All I will say is that I&rsquo;ve seen people wield them as weapons, instead of collaborating with people to use them. The criteria I evaluate technology by is pretty simple. Can I understand it? Does it make sense in my gut? This may seem like a simpletons view, but it&rsquo;s proven correct time &amp; again. Is it simple to understand &amp; work with quickly? How many layers of abstraction or indirection are there? What value do they add? Is there a simpler way to do it? Would other people understand what it&rsquo;s doing? How about in 5 years? Is it closed, open, popular? What does it feel like to use?</p>

<p>Microsoft Access &amp; ColdFusion still exist 13 years after I used them. Access 2013 looks like it&rsquo;s been given new Metro (sorry, Windows 8-style UI) &amp; web coats, but underneath it looks like the same animal that has not evolved in over a decade. There are rapid application development platforms &amp; tools out there, but why haven&rsquo;t they evolved, and become more widely used for application development? particularly enterprise systems development?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glitch in the Matrix]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/03/09/glitch-in-the-matrix/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/03/09/glitch-in-the-matrix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He sprinted, his powerful legs heaving with the strain of propelling his massive 6 foot 3 inch frame forward. His lungs sucked in as much air as they could in the short span they were allowed. They were gaining on him. Two distinct shapes in the distance. 17.2 meters &amp; closing.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>As he glanced back a few moments before he could just make out their features with the ambient lighting from the houses &amp; dim street lights. Their faces were wolf like, but sinister, hideously contorted. They were howling, but only he could hear it. Long ethereal tormented howls filled his night. His v-band augmented reality display identified them as level 6 ghosts. They were there, but not really there. The two runners were also wearing v-bands, and running in another part of the world. They were chosen by v-net as competitors and spawned on his run.</p>

<p>He chuckled to himself, as to them he appeared as Astro Boy. These young kids had no originality, thinking they could psych older runners. But this was serious. If he let them gain ground he risked his level 7 standing in the league.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Show my last ghost&rsquo; he said out loud while running, seemingly to himself. His previous self spawned in front of him, running his previous run. He could see he was slacking off &amp; the two wolf like ghosts were gaining. He forced his legs to increase his pace, and sucked in more oxygen. He started gaining on his past ghost &amp; pulling away from his pursuers.</p>

<p>Suddenly his vision went black, and then it was back, but instead of the familiar scene in front of him he saw trees densely packed together. He was in a forest. The scene was moving fast, bouncing up and down, left and right. He kept running straight along the path he was on, but couldn&rsquo;t see where he was going. His v-band was showing him someone from somewhere else. What the frak was happening!</p>

<p>All this happened in seconds, so he kept running, confused, and expecting that the v-band would correct itself. The scene from his v-band lurched as if the person fell, and then was facing up looking at the trees &amp; dark sky. The vision started to darken, but before it went completely dark he saw what looked like a primitive hunter standing over him. He looked big, muscly, but with short arms, and was carrying a large spear.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/15/running/">Running</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Software]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/24/creating-software/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/24/creating-software</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi my name is Peter and I&rsquo;m a developer, now playing an architect, and still trying to figure out what that means. But that&rsquo;s a post for another day. Probably many posts.</p>

<p>To put this post in context my background is mostly &lsquo;front end&rsquo; software development in DOS, Windows, Web, and Mobile; mostly with software that has a user interface, but occasionally not.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Complexity</h2>

<p>I have always struggled with software development complexity.</p>

<p>I love software development. Communicating &amp; collaborating with people and computers, thinking, planning, modelling, designing, delving into my creative mind &amp; soul, engineering and <em>crafting</em> software that fulfils a need, creating is … awesome!</p>

<p>Software development is complex, but I believe <em>we make it more complex</em>. In our quest to make software development better, we lose focus, and we end up creating complexity.</p>

<h2>Process</h2>

<p>Complexity can exist at many different steps in the software development journey. What do you do with something that&rsquo;s complex? You create a process to perform it of course.</p>

<p>Perhaps the most infamous process is the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waterfall_model">waterfall model</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>&lsquo;The waterfall model is a sequential design process, often used in software development processes, in which progress is seen as flowing steadily downwards (like a waterfall) through the phases of Conception, Initiation, Analysis, Design, Construction, Testing, Production/Implementation, and Maintenance.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Sounds great doesn&rsquo;t it? Follow a detailed plan, err &hellip; &lsquo;phases in a waterfall&rsquo;, and you will have software at the end of the process that fulfils your need. People have been following it for <em>decades</em>. There&rsquo;s only one problem.</p>

<blockquote><p>&lsquo;The first formal description of the waterfall model is often cited as a 1970 article by Winston W. Royce, although Royce did not use the term &ldquo;waterfall&rdquo; in this article. Royce presented this model as an example of a flawed, non-working model.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>But this didn&rsquo;t stop people from using it. <em>Still hasn&rsquo;t.</em> Perhaps there is perceived safety in process. If you follow instructions, surely you will achieve the desired end result?</p>

<p>On my first agile project we delivered a green fields software system in 8 months, which would have taken <em>years</em> using our traditional software development process, and this included learning an agile process, tools &amp; techniques. After the project ended I returned to one of the traditional software development areas. Two things struck me like physical blows, and left me with a feeling of complete loss &amp; bewilderment.</p>

<p>The first was that email was my process again. I sent more emails in that first day than in the previous 8 months. The second thing was when I was sitting in my little cubicle, nicely partitioned, I overheard a conversation between two developers &ndash; &ldquo;Reject defect #537. That&rsquo;s not a defect because&hellip;&rdquo; I forget the specifics, but remember that it was two developers, an absurd defect number, and they literally talked about it for 10 &ndash; 15 minutes. It never occurred to them that they should go find the tester &amp; <em>talk</em> to them.</p>

<h2>Technology</h2>

<p>Processes can be complex, and so can the dizzying universe of technology which is created &amp; wielded by people.</p>

<p>Programming languages are used to build software, and there are thousands of them, with more being created every year. Each one has it&rsquo;s own syntax (form) and semantics (meaning) for expressing it&rsquo;s instructions to a machine.</p>

<p>There are different types of software. For example operating systems manage hardware and provide services for other software. Platforms, frameworks, libraries, and applications use operating systems, and each other.</p>

<p>Each piece of software can be complex, and working software can be a complex web of relationships between them. Just how complex can be highlighted by a seemingly absurd comparison.</p>

<blockquote><p>&lsquo;For decades computer scientists have strived to build machines that can calculate faster than the human brain and store more information. The contraptions have won. &hellip; Biology does a lot with a little: the human genome, which grows our body and directs us through years of complex life, requires less data than a laptop operating system.&rsquo;</p>

<p>Mark Fischetti, <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=computers-vs-brains">Computers versus Brains</a><br/>
Scientific American, November, 2011</p></blockquote>

<p>It takes time to understand technology, when to use it, and how to apply it, and people often come away with different understanding, and a different level of skill in using it.</p>

<p>Early in my career I was working on a project when it was decided a well known services company (name withheld) would come in, save the day, and show us how to do it properly. There was one <em>recognised expert</em> I will always remember. He sat quietly aloof at his desk every day, apart from the occasional very important closed door meeting. Each day he would take from his desk a book from the vast array of &lsquo;software development&rsquo; books on it (his personal collection), sit there with it in front of his computer and implement some new form of <em>best practice</em> code or <em>pattern</em> for the part of the project he was working on. He was seen as highly productive.</p>

<p>When he left his masterpiece was given to me, with no hand over. You can guess the outcome. It was either the most brilliant code I have ever seen in my entire life, and I was unworthy to begin to comprehend it&rsquo;s magnificence, or it was a pile of shit. The truth was probably somewhere in the middle.</p>

<p>The sad thing is I&rsquo;ve seen this behaviour to varying degrees <em>consistently</em> over the years. It&rsquo;s something I have been guilty of as well. People wielding technology, rather than collaborating with people using technology.</p>

<h2>Simplicity</h2>

<p>When I think about software development I think about the following words in a positive, <em>great</em> context.</p>

<p>People.<br/>
Purpose.<br/>
Knowledge.<br/>
Capability.<br/>
Humility.<br/>
Communication.<br/>
Collaboration.<br/>
Compromise.<br/>
Consistency.<br/>
Passion.<br/>
Time.<br/>
Technology.<br/>
Simplicity.</p>

<p>I put people first. They are the enduring <em>thread</em> that ties man to machine, and getting it to do what they want. Process &amp; Technology seem to forget that sometimes.</p>

<p>I put technology second last. Without everything before it, it is useless.</p>

<p>I put simplicity last. I believe it will <em>emerge</em> if you have the rest.</p>

<p>If only we had all of these things, all of the time.</p>

<p>You can create software without some of these things, but not <em>great</em> software.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/15/running/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/15/running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He was running. <em>Hard.</em> He knew instinctively to the very fibre of his being why he was running. Survival. His life. If he didn&rsquo;t run, and run fast, he was dead.</p>

<p>They were after him, howling for blood, and a more primal drive, the thrill of the hunt, and the kill. He was the prey.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>His hunters were larger than him, bigger boned, with barrel chests, shorter arms &amp; legs, but more powerful. They carried more primitive heavy stabbing spears compared to his more versatile throwing spear, which meant they needed to get close to him.</p>

<p>He knew they were getting closer. The sounds of their heavy footfalls rang through the dense forest. Their garbled grunts &amp; taunts echoed all around him, their purpose to intimidate, to frighten, but they caused the opposite reaction, it triggered his survival instinct. He ran faster.</p>

<p>Suddenly he tripped over a branch, and fell hard hitting his head on a rock. As his vision darkened, he felt like he was being thrown through something strange. And then there was total darkness. An enveloped feeling. No sound. No predators. And then, again, strangely, but differently &hellip;</p>

<p>He was running. Steadily. Consistently. Really concentrating on his breathing, his stride, the way his feet hit the ground, and his overall rhythm. He was running for fitness, competing against imagined binary ghosts, some of other souls &ndash; thousands of them scattered around the planet, but also some of himself at different places in time, but in his mind mostly against ones from the past.</p>

<p>His mind created the purpose &amp; the urgency for his running. The small computing device attached to his body was capable of storing &amp; processing massive amounts of data. While he ran it was working to pump high beats per minute music to his ears which when combined with his brain increased his heart rate &amp; blood flow.</p>

<p>The small computing device was also working to receive signals being broadcast from an array of satellites orbiting the planet, to triangulate his exact location on the planet every second. It then sent this information back into the airwaves, to be captured by a vast array of computing devices &amp; software, which then stored &amp; analysed the information, and sent back statistics &amp; insights that he could analyse, share, and interact with later.</p>

<p>He looked ahead as he ran at the scenery slowly bobbing up &amp; down, up &amp; down. He pulled more air into his lungs. This was different. Strange. Somewhat lonely, but not. He couldn&rsquo;t figure out why, but it felt good to run.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[#failmeaningfully]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/01/01/failmeaningfully/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/01/01/failmeaningfully</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was August 2010. Over 2 years ago. My beautiful daughter Abigail was 2 years old. The iPhone 4 had just come out, and the smartphone revolution was in full swing. All I needed was an idea. Somehow I found myself become part of a like minded, passionate &amp; committed team, with some of the best people I have ever had the privilege or pleasure to work with. I say somehow because I&rsquo;ve always tried to go with the flow. It just happened. Redistore was born.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2013-01-01-failmeaningfully/WebSite1.png" width="569" height="635" title="Redistore Web Site" ></p>

<!--more-->


<p>The idea &amp; vision was simple. Wouldn&rsquo;t it be cool if you could order &amp; pay for your coffee <em>before</em> you arrived at the store, just waltz in, bypass the queue, pick it up &amp; go. It&rsquo;s paid for so there&rsquo;s no fumbling around for change, or paying with a card which was time consuming before contactless payment, e.g. MasterCard PayPass. I thought the idea had potential. The team thought the idea had potential. People we talked to thought the idea had potential. We decided as a team to take a risk. &lsquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Field_of_Dreams">If you build it, he will come</a>&rsquo;, we all heard the voice whisper. Others were skeptical, but not us. We built it.</p>

<p>2 years later, and Redistore has failed. This is what I learnt.</p>

<h2>Reality</h2>

<p>I can still remember how it started. The excitement of exploring the idea. Formulating it. Talking about it. Becoming a team. It felt awesome. That&rsquo;s the Hollywood beginning.</p>

<p>The reality was a hard slog of trying to work two jobs. 15 to 16 hour days, 5 to 6 days a week. Rise at 6am, cycle to work &amp; be working by 7am. Leave at 4pm. Be home &amp; sorted by 5pm. Two hours to spend with my family, which I&rsquo;m guilty of not doing enough of. At work by 7pm. Work till 9pm or 10pm. Rinse &amp; repeat. And don&rsquo;t forget the weekends. You get the picture. I had no life.</p>

<h2>Tech</h2>

<p><em>But</em> we built something that&rsquo;s bloody cool &amp; has possibility. A fully customisable, real time online ordering system for low value, high volume consumables. Coffee stores. Take away food. The order is paid for by the customer using their Redistore account which they can &lsquo;top up&rsquo; using PayPal or a Credit Card. The store gets a verified order. It&rsquo;s in real time. There&rsquo;s no queueing. Win win.</p>

<p>The technology &amp; platform that we built was the fun part.</p>

<p>The customer web client was built using Sencha ExtJS 3 and supports all major browsers. It was designed &amp; built from scratch to provide a <em>fast</em> UX (User Experience) for browsing stores &amp; ordering, unlike most classic page request &amp; response web stores. ExtJS is an amazing platform, but has a steep learning curve, and ExtJS 4 broke compatibility for ExtJS 3 apps; there is significant work required to upgrade your app.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2013-01-01-failmeaningfully/WebClient1.png" width="795" height="600" title="Redistore Web Site" ></p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2013-01-01-failmeaningfully/WebClient2.png" width="795" height="600" title="Redistore Web Site" ></p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2013-01-01-failmeaningfully/WebClient3.png" width="795" height="600" title="Redistore Web Site" ></p>

<p>The now defunct customer mobile client was built using Sencha Touch 1. The native vs. web app mobile holy war was raging, and we decided to build a web app. It was a mistake. The mobile client worked adequately on iOS, but on Android it was unusable. The tools were not ready. Facebook had not yet <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/09/11/mark-zuckerberg-our-biggest-mistake-with-mobile-was-betting-too-much-on-html5/">admitted their mistake</a>, nor Sencha fired their <a href="http://www.sencha.com/blog/the-making-of-fastbook-an-html5-love-story/">Fastbook</a> return. We needed a <em>great</em> customer UX, and didn&rsquo;t have it.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox left" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2013-01-01-failmeaningfully/iPhoneApp1.png" width="320" height="548" title="Redistore iPhone App" ></p>

<p>The store receiver client was also built with Sencha Touch, and performs adequately for stores on an iPod.</p>

<p>The web clients communicate via Ajax to the back end action style JSON based web services developed using .NET WCF. If building using the same core technology now, we&rsquo;d seriously look at Web API &amp; RESTful services. There&rsquo;s also a ton of awesome back-end enterprise system type stuff (database, reconciliation, reporting, MI etc.), that was built by a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cylon_(Battlestar_Galactica)">Cylon</a>. Seriously. They work <em>hard</em>, I guess because they don&rsquo;t need to sleep.</p>

<p>To address the <em>great</em> customer mobile UX, after go-live we spent 3 months building a native iPhone app, and 3 months building a native Android app. It was a great learning experience at the cost of 6 months of effort. Without getting into details of our approach, or religious debates, I hope that we (the industry) can move <strong>forward</strong> to <em>the web</em>. How we do that is for <a href="http://www.okito.net/post/38255553240/the-mobile-web">smart people</a> to <a href="http://lilly.tumblr.com/post/38309067913/asymmetry">work out</a>.</p>

<h2>Go Live</h2>

<p>We went live on Friday 1st April 2011 (oh the irony) after 8 months of intense development. There were teething problems as with any new production system, and we worked through them to get it to a stable state.</p>

<p>We tried to sell it mostly to coffee stores the old fashioned way, by approaching them, talking to them about it, showing them what it could do. Once we had a store on board we did really simple customer advertising at the store.</p>

<p>Although it&rsquo;s <em>far</em> from being a runaway success, it has &amp; continues to be <em>successful</em>, in that it ticks along &amp; is used every single business day, with no issues.</p>

<p>Over 18 months in production, what are the stats?</p>

<ul>
<li>250 accounts. 43 active in November 2012. 68 with a balance > $5.</li>
<li>5 stores. 2 active.</li>
<li>4,712 orders (multiple items per order). 63% using web. 36% using mobile.</li>
<li>1,900 top ups (min $5 per top up).</li>
</ul>


<p>The order percentages between web &amp; mobile are interesting. The 2 active stores are located in office buildings, and it implies customers prefer using the web client to order from their desks, before going down to pickup their order.</p>

<h2>Reflection</h2>

<p>The enthusiasm &amp; commitment for the idea &amp; vision has dispersed. What it could have been didn&rsquo;t materialise, and not by lack of effort.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t think we really understood our customer, as we really just replaced phone orders. We didn&rsquo;t have an automated store onboarding process, so bringing stores on was a long complicated process. We didn&rsquo;t do marketing.</p>

<p>We took a gamble, and it didn&rsquo;t pay off. We failed.</p>

<h2>End</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s time to move on. To take what I&rsquo;ve learnt &amp; move forward. I&rsquo;m excited about seeking new ideas &amp; projects. Exploring. Finding. Trying. I love the process of creating things. I&rsquo;ve heard the expression &lsquo;<strong>fail fast</strong>&rsquo;, but I think you should &lsquo;<strong>fail meaningfully</strong>&rsquo; at something you choose, have <a href="http://www.zurb.com/article/1131/passion-to-fail-fast">passion</a>
 for, believe in, and work hard at. Learning takes quality time.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s time to move on … <em>after</em> I finish reading <a href="http://theleanstartup.com">The Lean Startup</a> by Eric Ries.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demon Hacker]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2012/09/01/demon-hacker/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T16:05:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2012/09/01/demon-hacker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In early 1995 (17 years ago) I created an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MS-DOS">MS-DOS</a>
app called Demon Hacker.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s purpose was to enable a user to patch (rather crudely, but effectively)
PC games files &amp; their created saved game files to cheat.</p>

<p>I got more of a kick out of building the app using
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turbo_Pascal">Turbo Pascal</a>, and giving it to my friends
to use than I did playing &amp; cheating in the games.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>17 years is a <em>long</em> time in computer technology. In 1995 the Internet was emerging, and
I knew that it had been put on a few FTP sites, but could I find it now?</p>

<p>After a few minutes with Google I had found &amp; downloaded the ZIP file.
(And made sure to scan it with antivirus software).</p>

<p><em>Wow!</em></p>

<p>The problem now was that it was a 16-bit MS-DOS app.</p>

<p>With only Mac OS X Mountain Lion, and Windows 7, both 64-bit, I thought I would have
to resort to setting up a VM (Virtual Machine).</p>

<p>Another Google and I found <a href="http://www.dosbox.com">DOSBox</a>.
I download &amp; opened DOSBox on Mac OS X.</p>

<p><em>Double wow!</em></p>

<p>I now had a directory listing. Look at those dates!</p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2012-09-01-demon-hacker/dir.png" title="Demon Hacker" ></p>

<p>Check out DEMON.EXE. That&rsquo;s 29,408 bytes for the main application.
UI (User Interface).
Logic.
Everything.
That&rsquo;s 29 kilobytes (KB).</p>

<p><em>Holy crap!</em></p>

<p>Next step, would it run?</p>

<p><em>BOOM!</em></p>

<p>An app that I had created 17 years ago was running in a DOS emulator on my
MAC OS X system.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2012-09-01-demon-hacker/run.png" title="Demon Hacker" ></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the proof &ndash; the help screen. You have to admit, it&rsquo;s very helpful :)</p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2012-09-01-demon-hacker/run-help.png" title="Demon Hacker" ></p>

<p>It even supports in that 29 KB size changing the application font to a medieval
type font. Typical font files are MB these days.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2012-09-01-demon-hacker/run-font.png" title="Demon Hacker" ></p>

<p>The great thing about Demon Hacker is that it was open.
Extendable.
Anyone with a PC game, a HEX editor, and some spare time could create hacks
for games by editing the DEMON.DAT text file.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>{
</span><span class='line'>    Alone in the Dark
</span><span class='line'>save[0..5].itd
</span><span class='line'>save??.itd
</span><span class='line'>//25700 oil for the lamp
</span><span class='line'>19856,64
</span><span class='line'>19857,64
</span><span class='line'>//25700 rifle ammo
</span><span class='line'>19866,64
</span><span class='line'>19867,64
</span><span class='line'>//25700 health points
</span><span class='line'>19882,64
</span><span class='line'>19883,64
</span><span class='line'>//25700 pistol ammo
</span><span class='line'>20024,64
</span><span class='line'>20025,64
</span><span class='line'>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>And Demon Hacker would then let anyone use that cheat.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox" src="http://www.peterboni.net/media/images/2012-09-01-demon-hacker/hack.png" title="Demon Hacker" ></p>

<p>If only GitHub had existed back in 1995 the source code may not have been lost.
If you&rsquo;re feeling nostalgic get DOSBox, your old games, and get
<a href="http://www.github.com/peterboni/demonhacker">Demon Hacker</a>.</p>

<p>This trip back down memory lane has reminded me of a few things.
The Internet, WWW, Google &amp; technology are amazing things.
Also that i&rsquo;m a hacker, and always will be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
