<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-15T21:29:07+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/</id><title type="html">Peter Boni</title><subtitle>Trying to not take myself too seriously.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Legacy</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2017/12/15/legacy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Legacy" /><published>2017-12-15T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2017/12/15/legacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2017/12/15/legacy/">&lt;p&gt;Sam Newman started it again. Not the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sam_Newman&quot;&gt;controversial one&lt;/a&gt;. The one who wrote the book on Microservices, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com.au/Building-Microservices-Designing-Fine-Grained-Systems-ebook/dp/B00T3N7XB4&quot;&gt;literally&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think I first heard the term ‘heritage’ from @peterboni, but I could be totally wrong…”, Sam Newman - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/samnewman/status/929737855840202752&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a problem with a few words the IT industry chooses to use for a while now. &lt;em&gt;Legacy&lt;/em&gt; is one of them. The other one is &lt;em&gt;resource&lt;/em&gt;, but that’s a post for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“My other quest is to replace ‘resource’ with ‘people’ in our vocabulary. Resource is an inanimate not special object you can create and destroy. Do not like it used in relation to tech people.”, Peter Boni - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peterboni/status/941448649019502593&quot;&gt;Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People in the IT industry often refer to &lt;em&gt;older&lt;/em&gt; business systems as legacy, usually in the following situations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s become hard and/or expensive to find people who have the skills for, or that even want to work on it, or it’s inherited by new people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s technology architecture or components are no longer fit for purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s never because the new technology is &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/93lrosBEW-Q&quot;&gt;Shiny&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how fast the IT industry is changing, in the above situations, legacy is often said with a certain mindset, and a level of disgust, or disdain. It carries a certain stigma, despite the fact that the business was probably built up on, and is now heavily reliant on the legacy business systems. It’s adding &lt;em&gt;value&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started using a new word a while ago to refer to older business systems. Like Sam Newman, I’m not sure where I heard or read it, but it stuck in my mind. See, words have meaning and power. I didn’t want to refer to business systems that I helped build over many years with disgust or disdain, or more importantly for other people to hear that in what I was saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word I started using is &lt;em&gt;heritage&lt;/em&gt;. To me it implies that an older business system is &lt;em&gt;valued&lt;/em&gt;, and that it should be cared for by being improved, incrementally over time, while continuing to add value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, there will come a time when it’s not appropriate or even feasible to continue to do this, and then it’s important to understand and agree not only the reasons for replacing it, but the investment required to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Work" /><summary type="html">Sam Newman started it again. Not the controversial one. The one who wrote the book on Microservices, literally.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flow</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2016/02/06/flow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flow" /><published>2016-02-06T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-02-06T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2016/02/06/flow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2016/02/06/flow/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;theory&quot;&gt;Theory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve just started one of my 2016 challenges, which is to read one &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt; book a month. An achievable goal for a slow reader with a busy life. I like to absorb, think about, and, more importantly, &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; what I’m reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My book for February (January was my holiday month) was originally published in 1990. &lt;strong&gt;Flow: The Psychology of Happiness&lt;/strong&gt; by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi (good luck pronouncing that) is “The Classic Work on How to Achieve Happiness”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter 2 “The Anatomy of Consciousness” talks about how we are at a time in history where the ability to control oneself is not held in high esteem. This is unlike previous periods in history when certain cultures did not accept people as members of the community unless they could master their thoughts and feelings. The chapter describes with great insight what consciousness is, and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;practice&quot;&gt;Practice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I deliberately chose my first book to complement another 2016 challenge - learn how to meditate. I’ve been using a simple app called “buddhify”, which you can think of as “mindfulness for the digital generation”. With the app on my iPhone, I play short (5 to 10 minutes) guided targeted meditations in the morning when traveling to work, during the day, and at night before going to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app has a beautiful user interface for selecting which meditation you would like to play and even subtly suggests which type you should use based on the time of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-light-border img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2016-02-06-flow/Play.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also stats, but I haven’t felt the need to look at them during the week for motivation. I do think it’s interesting reflecting that consistently doing short meditations each day really adds up by the end of the week. This week I spent 1.4 hours meditating. I can feel the effect of a short meditation on my mind and body, so it will be interesting to see the cumulative long-term impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-light-border img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2016-02-06-flow/Stats.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buddhify.com&quot;&gt;buddhify.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">Theory</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2 Years of Running Notes</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2015/01/10/2-years-of-running-notes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 Years of Running Notes" /><published>2015-01-10T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-01-10T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2015/01/10/2-years-of-running-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2015/01/10/2-years-of-running-notes/">&lt;p&gt;“How did it go, Peter?” is the placeholder that greets me in the Notes section when completing a run using RunKeeper. It’s unobtrusive, yet alluring. If you have not noticed it yet, it looks like this. It’s sandwiched between your run statistics and the obtrusive social media &lt;em&gt;swagger mode&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-light-border img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2015-01-10-2-years-of-running-notes/notes.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started running on January 2, 2013 (a new years resolution started one day late), I thought “I’m going to write something in there”. Here is what I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Breathless. Running = hard!!!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;1 Jan 2013, 2.55 km, 6:42 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was after an embarrassing (only in hindsight) run. I didn’t even run the full distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve now been running consistently for 2 years, and in that time decided to write &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; into the alluring “How did it go, Peter?” about 70% of the time. Here are the major themes I’ve categorised the running notes into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously I felt hungry enough during this run to justify the use of the word juicy twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People cooking juicy juicy BBQ steak &amp;amp; sausages at night when I go running should be shot.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;18 Jan 2013, 5.22 km, 6:40 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I had the wrong type of food before a run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bleh. Cake NOT like run!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;22 Jan 2013, 5.27 km, 7:11 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learn to love the pain (with 2 beers)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;20 Dec 2013, 2.84 km, 4:39 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course sometimes I didn’t have enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Insufficient Input&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;4 Apr 2014, 5.08 km, 5:24 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-through-the-motions&quot;&gt;Go through the motions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I felt like an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Object-&amp;gt;Eat,Sleep,Work,Repeat&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;8 Apr 2014, 4.16 km, 5:13 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or was trying to outrun the residue of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Shit run for a shit week.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;14 Mar 2014, 4.32 km, 6:03 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or was on autopilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Can’t be fu..ahh, “Recovery”. Yeah. That’s it. Recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;5 Jun 2014, 5.11 km, 6:00 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hill&quot;&gt;The Hill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me introduce you to my nemesis. The Hill. It is not just &lt;em&gt;a hill&lt;/em&gt;. It is a &lt;em&gt;foreboding presence&lt;/em&gt;. Just looking at a photo of it fills me with dread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/2015-01-10-2-years-of-running-notes/the-hill.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-light-border img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2015-01-10-2-years-of-running-notes/the-hill-small.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I try to ignore it, it calls to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From its shadow I feel it’s pull. Come. Climb me. I am. The Hill.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;5 Mar 2014, 3.14 km, 5:12 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I finally give in, or find myself attempting to run up it and not knowing how I got there, it asserts itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Hill Angry!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;7 Mar 2014, 6.75 km, 5:52 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then sometimes, just sometimes, I put the wrong things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The one that I punish The Hill.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;22 Apr 2014, 4.13 km, 5:17 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a special section of The Hill which is called &lt;em&gt;The Paul&lt;/em&gt;, when run in reverse, as fast as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Paul&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;16 Jun 2014, 0.71 km, 3:28 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feeling-good&quot;&gt;Feeling Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I kept running was because of the &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt;. I loved it, and it’s reflected in the majority of my running notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From Friday to Sunday I Make My Girls Go Wild&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;12 Jul 2013, 4.01 km, 5:30 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I won’t even make it to the shore without your light…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;20 Oct 2013, 7.03 km, 5:28 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Couldn’t change the magnetism at this rate I’m traveling&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;02 Dec 2013, 3.89 km, 5:03 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;3 “The Hill” - This is My Clarity&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;06 Jan 2014, 7.02 km, 5:58 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chilly Bright not Stormy Night, but still … Paradise&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;14 Jun 2014, 3.09 km, 4:58 min/km&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other 30% of the time I didn’t write a running note. Sometimes you just need to run. Try putting your feelings and thoughts into a running note after your next run.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">“How did it go, Peter?” is the placeholder that greets me in the Notes section when completing a run using RunKeeper. It’s unobtrusive, yet alluring. If you have not noticed it yet, it looks like this. It’s sandwiched between your run statistics and the obtrusive social media swagger mode.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Consistency</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/12/20/consistency/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Consistency" /><published>2014-12-20T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-12-20T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/12/20/consistency</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/12/20/consistency/">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2014/01/01/running-numbers/&quot;&gt;January&lt;/a&gt; I paid RunKeeper to use the data I gave them the previous year, and give me insight. The numbers and charts were disappointing. This wasn’t insight I thought to myself. I wrote that what mattered was the experience. One year later and RunKeeper still charge you for insight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-12-20-consistency/rk-insights1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-12-20-consistency/rk-insights2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered that RunKeeper enables you to export your data. ‘Get your export on’ as RunKeeper says. I downloaded my activity data as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comma-separated_values&quot;&gt;CSV&lt;/a&gt;, and attempted to analyse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do with lots of data? Add up the numbers of course. I wanted to compare the last 2 years. The numbers were again disappointing. They didn’t tell me anything interesting that I didn’t already know. More workouts meant more duration and calories burned. Less cycling meant less distance and climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time to visualise the data for 2014 with some charts. Maybe charts would give me &lt;em&gt;insight&lt;/em&gt;. First I charted workout duration, with a linear trend line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-12-20-consistency/workouts-duration.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trend line showed me that my workout time had increased during the year. Combined with the data points a picture of &lt;em&gt;consistency&lt;/em&gt; over the year emerged. I had a sudden realisation. I knew this already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RunKeeper app has a ‘workouts per week’ chart on the ‘Me’ tab. It’s a simple and effective visual of how many workouts you do per week, for the last 10 weeks. I realised that I had been using it during the year to motivate myself. I had been aiming for at least 3 workouts per week. If I fell behind one week, I would workout more the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-12-20-consistency/rk-workouts-weekly.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I charted workouts per week, with a monthly moving average trend line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-12-20-consistency/workouts-weekly.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chart showed me a picture of where my consistency changed. In February I went on a work trip to New Zealand and San Francisco, and in April I had a few weeks holiday. Of course the data doesn’t tell the full story. I did a lot of walking in New Zealand and San Francisco which I didn’t record in RunKeeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wearable devices wave is coming. We will be capturing more data about ourselves than ever before. This will create many possibilities, and raise many more questions. We need to use these devices to enhance our &lt;em&gt;experience&lt;/em&gt;, and drive our &lt;em&gt;consistency&lt;/em&gt;. And remember you don’t need to pay for &lt;em&gt;insight&lt;/em&gt;. Just do it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">In January I paid RunKeeper to use the data I gave them the previous year, and give me insight. The numbers and charts were disappointing. This wasn’t insight I thought to myself. I wrote that what mattered was the experience. One year later and RunKeeper still charge you for insight.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">City to Surf</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/09/08/city-to-surf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="City to Surf" /><published>2014-09-08T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-09-08T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/09/08/city-to-surf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/09/08/city-to-surf/">&lt;p&gt;This is a challenge to my future 2015 self, for the City to Surf 12km run. Beat this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 2013 Self&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-09-08-city-to-surf/2013.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 2014 Self&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-09-08-city-to-surf/2014.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Average pace: 30 seconds per km faster next year!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">This is a challenge to my future 2015 self, for the City to Surf 12km run. Beat this!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/06/27/running/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running" /><published>2014-06-27T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-06-27T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/06/27/running</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/06/27/running/">&lt;p&gt;Just passed the Christadelphian Meeting Hall on my nightly run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JESUS WILL BE KING ON EARTH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I glanced left and saw what appeared to be a dwarf from The Lord of the Rings … running. Full length braided hair to his legs. Full beard. Black t-shirt and jeans. Huge biceps. All that was missing was a battle axe and shield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I swear I haven’t been drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-06-27-running/photo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Running" /><category term="Story" /><summary type="html">Just passed the Christadelphian Meeting Hall on my nightly run.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Circular</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/05/19/circular/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Circular" /><published>2014-05-19T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-05-19T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/05/19/circular</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/05/19/circular/">&lt;p&gt;As his body left the bus, and his foot struck the pavement, time slowed. His thoughts went immediately to the unknown man and he dreaded the unintelligible call “G.. y.. b.. i.. h…”, like a gong mechanically sounding the impending end of the world. The unknown man always appeared the same; raggedy unwashed hair, unshaven, old dirty clothing. His thoughts moved away from the unknown man, and he headed for the gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He walked along the path, early morning sunlight shining down through the criss-crossed metal gate, hitting the left hand side of his face. His eyes closed, seemingly by themselves to shield against the bright light. He contemplated the warmth of the sun on his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reluctantly he willed his eyes to slowly open. They squinted and then closed again. Black bars rolled over his closed eyelids as he walked, in a hypnotic rhythm, the effect of the sunlight being blocked by the metal that formed the gate squares. He found it harder to will his eyes open as he walked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When his eyes closed he could hear and experience parts of the world that were before drowned out by his visual sense. He heard the sounds of the people around him. Walking. Stomping. Stopping. Starting. Conversing. The birds. Cars. Buses. The cacophony was strangely familiar. He felt himself being pulled past the unknown man, as time began to slowly speed back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“G.. y.. b.. i.. h…” the unknown man intoned. He couldn’t make out what the man was saying, but the way the man spoke synced with his walking, the sunlight and black bars, the sounds. There was rhythm. Everything was moving together. It was coming again, he could hear it before the man began, “G.. y.. b.. i.. h…”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then suddenly it was all gone. As his body left the bus, and his foot struck the pavement, time slowed. He had the feeling that he had been here before.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Story" /><summary type="html">As his body left the bus, and his foot struck the pavement, time slowed. His thoughts went immediately to the unknown man and he dreaded the unintelligible call “G.. y.. b.. i.. h…”, like a gong mechanically sounding the impending end of the world. The unknown man always appeared the same; raggedy unwashed hair, unshaven, old dirty clothing. His thoughts moved away from the unknown man, and he headed for the gate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PhotoArchive 1.3</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/04/26/photoarchive-1-dot-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhotoArchive 1.3" /><published>2014-04-26T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-04-26T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/04/26/photoarchive-1-dot-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/04/26/photoarchive-1-dot-3/">&lt;p&gt;PhotoArchive version 1.3 is now available. With version 1.3 you can now easily archive to your home storage &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; your cloud (Google Drive) storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://googleblog.blogspot.com.au/2014/03/save-more-with-google-drive.html&quot;&gt;recently lowered&lt;/a&gt; the price of their monthly storage plans making it extremely cheap to have an active (not cold like Amazon S3 Glacier Storage) offsite backup of your irreplaceable memories, your photos &amp;amp; videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/EzUwVVtSrxs&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Apps" /><category term="Mobile" /><summary type="html">PhotoArchive version 1.3 is now available. With version 1.3 you can now easily archive to your home storage and your cloud (Google Drive) storage.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running Conversation</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/03/03/running-conversation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running Conversation" /><published>2014-03-03T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-03-03T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/03/03/running-conversation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/03/03/running-conversation/">&lt;p&gt;I was out running early this morning, and RunKeeper had just finished coldly relating the
facts of my run performance so far. I wasn’t doing great, but in my defence I was sore from the full-body workout the day before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t wear a watch, and I wanted to know what time it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music was playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(press+hold button)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s the time?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s 6:20 am, much too early!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laughed, and then thought…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(press+hold button)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s on my schedule for this morning?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have an appointment at 10:00am. Would you like to hear more about it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At 10 am, Liam Swimming Lessons, at *** Swimming Pool”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool, I had forgot about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(press button)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music resumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s next? conversing with your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/ios/carplay/&quot;&gt;car&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re living in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Running" /><summary type="html">I was out running early this morning, and RunKeeper had just finished coldly relating the
facts of my run performance so far. I wasn’t doing great, but in my defence I was sore from the full-body workout the day before.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PhotoArchive for iPhone</title><link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/02/15/photoarchive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhotoArchive for iPhone" /><published>2014-02-15T07:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-02-15T07:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/02/15/photoarchive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/02/15/photoarchive/">&lt;p&gt;I take a lot of photos &amp;amp; videos with my iPhone. It’s always with me, so it’s convenient, and the quality is good. My DSLR body and lenses produce superior quality, but are usually left at home gathering dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I take new photos or videos, often of my family, I worry that if something were to happen to my iPhone, those irreplaceable memories will be lost forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many solutions for this need, for example iCloud Backup, the Dropbox app, or the Amazon Cloud Drive app, but they all have varying costs and limitations. I wanted a simple solution for me, and that’s why I decided to build an app as a side project - PhotoArchive for iPhone. When released, PhotoArchive will be free for everyone on the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-it-looks-like&quot;&gt;What it looks like&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-02-15-photoarchive/iphone-black.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-center&quot; src=&quot;/img/2014-02-15-photoarchive/iphone-white.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-it-does&quot;&gt;What it does&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a Western Digital My Book NAS (Network Attached Storage) at home that is always on. I use it for file storage for computers on the network, and DLNA streaming to the living room TV via the PS3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I copy new photos &amp;amp; videos from my and my wife’s iPhones by manually connecting them to a computer via USB, and downloading the new ones. Because it’s a tedious manual process I don’t do it as often as I should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What PhotoArchive does is copy new photos &amp;amp; videos from your iOS device to an FTP server, over Wi-Fi. The Western Digital My Book NAS, like most NAS, supports FTP (File Transfer Protocol).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that when I get home I can effortlessly back up new photos &amp;amp; videos I’ve taken that day - no turning on computers, no USB cables etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-it-does-marketing-version&quot;&gt;What it does (marketing version)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does PhotoArchive do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;PhotoArchive saves your irreplaceable memories, your photos &amp;amp; videos from your iPhone, iPad, or iPod touch to your home storage over Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save Time&lt;/strong&gt; - Stop manually backing up your device to iTunes. Are you still using a USB cable? Stop manually backing up your photos &amp;amp; videos by importing them into iPhoto. You may still import them into iPhoto, but you can do it when you have time, not when you have to - your photos &amp;amp; videos are already safe!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Save Money&lt;/strong&gt; - Use iCloud Backup to back up everything except your Camera Roll, so there is no need to manually back up your device to iTunes. Turn off the Camera Roll from iCloud Backup, and stay under the 5.0 GB free limit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Archives&lt;/strong&gt; - Does not synchronise. Will not download photos or videos from your home storage to your device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never Deletes&lt;/strong&gt; - Will never delete a photo or video from your home storage, or from your device.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Archive&lt;/strong&gt; - Remembers the previous archive, and will only upload new photos &amp;amp; videos, so it’s &lt;em&gt;FAST&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Photo View&lt;/strong&gt; - Shows you your photos &amp;amp; videos that are in danger of being lost forever (not archived), and the ones that are safe in the event that something happens to your device (archived).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Resolution and Metadata&lt;/strong&gt; - Uploads your photos &amp;amp; videos in their full resolution, with all metadata - information about your photos &amp;amp; videos, e.g. where you took them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does PhotoArchive work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PhotoArchive archives to your home storage - NAS (Network Attached Storage) or Mac/PC, using FTP (File Transfer Protocol). Most NAS devices already support FTP, but if you are using a Mac/PC you will need an FTP server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FTP should only be used on Wi-Fi with WPA2 security, with your storage on the same network. Don’t do it over the Internet! Be security smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design-thinking&quot;&gt;Design thinking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main view that greets the user visually shows them all photos &amp;amp; videos on their iOS device, grouped into state - not archived, or archived. It first shows photos &amp;amp; videos that are not archived (in danger of being lost forever), and then photos &amp;amp; videos that are archived (safe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user can either setup their archive destination, or start archiving if already setup and there are new photos or videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took inspiration from the iOS Photos app, and show photos &amp;amp; videos as varying square sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Not Archived section photos &amp;amp; videos are shown as large squares up to a certain number, and then get smaller. Large squares let you see the few photos &amp;amp; videos that you haven’t archived up close. If there’s lots, then they are shown as small squares to give you a visual sense of how many there are. The section header is the PhotoArchive logo on red - danger!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Archived section shows photos &amp;amp; videos as small squares; they are safe, so you don’t need to see what they are, just get a visual sense of how many there are. The section header is the PhotoArchive logo on blue (this is the app icon) - safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design allows both sections to appear together on the main view without much scrolling required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-will-it-be-released&quot;&gt;When will it be released&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PhotoArchive is functionally complete. I’m currently cleaning, polishing and testing it. It would be great to have a few testers, so if you’d like to test it out and are willing to provide feedback, then contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;peter.boni@gmail.com&quot;&gt;peter.boni@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the purpose of PhotoArchive is to save your irreplaceable memories, i’ve thought about adding support for offsite archiving to cloud storage such as Amazon S3 or Glacier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Glacier is attractive because of it’s extreme lost cost - USD$0.01 per GB (gigabyte) per month. That’s just over USD$10 per month to archive 1TB (terabyte) of photos &amp;amp; videos!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Peter Boni</name></author><category term="Apps" /><category term="Design" /><category term="Dev" /><category term="Mobile" /><summary type="html">I take a lot of photos &amp;amp; videos with my iPhone. It’s always with me, so it’s convenient, and the quality is good. My DSLR body and lenses produce superior quality, but are usually left at home gathering dust.</summary></entry></feed>
