<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: story | Peter Boni]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/categories/story/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-06T12:45:27+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.peterboni.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Boni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/06/27/running/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-27T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/06/27/running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just passed the Christadelphian Meeting Hall on my nightly run. JESUS WILL BE KING ON EARTH.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I glanced left and saw what appeared to be a dwarf from The Lord of the Rings &hellip; running. Full length braided hair to his legs. Full beard. Black t-shirt and jeans. Huge biceps. All that was missing was a battle axe and shield. I swear I haven&rsquo;t been drinking.</p>

<p><img src="/media/images/2014-06-27-running/photo.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Circular]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/05/19/circular/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-19T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/05/19/circular</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As his body left the bus, and his foot struck the pavement, time slowed. His thoughts went immediately to the unknown man and he dreaded the unintelligible call &ldquo;G.. y.. b.. i.. h&hellip;&rdquo;, like a gong mechanically sounding the impending end of the world. The unknown man always appeared the same; raggedy unwashed hair, unshaven, old dirty clothing. His thoughts moved away from the unknown man, and he headed for the gate.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>He walked along the path, early morning sunlight shining down through the criss-crossed metal gate, hitting the left hand side of his face. His eyes closed, seemingly by themselves to shield against the bright light. He contemplated the warmth of the sun on his face.</p>

<p>Reluctantly he willed his eyes to slowly open. They squinted and then closed again. Black bars rolled over his closed eyelids as he walked, in a hypnotic rhythm, the effect of the sunlight being blocked by the metal that formed the gate squares. He found it harder to will his eyes open as he walked.</p>

<p>When his eyes closed he could hear and experience parts of the world that were before drowned out by his visual sense. He heard the sounds of the people around him. Walking. Stomping. Stopping. Starting. Conversing. The birds. Cars. Buses. The cacophony was strangely familiar. He felt himself being pulled past the unknown man, as time began to slowly speed back up.</p>

<p>&ldquo;G.. y.. b.. i.. h&hellip;&rdquo; the unknown man intoned. He couldn&rsquo;t make out what the man was saying, but the way the man spoke synced with his walking, the sunlight and black bars, the sounds. There was rhythm. Everything was moving together. It was coming again, he could hear it before the man began, &ldquo;G.. y.. b.. i.. h&hellip;&rdquo;.</p>

<p>And then suddenly it was all gone. As his body left the bus, and his foot struck the pavement, time slowed. He had the feeling that he had been here before.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Memory]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/07/25/running-memory/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-25T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/07/25/running-memory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Liam ran, his long muscular legs pounding the pavement. There were only a few souls out that chose to brave the cold and darkness of the early morning. His breathing and rhythm were steady. He wasn&rsquo;t pushing himself as he settled into his run. He ran to relax and be with his thoughts.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>&ldquo;Show dad running&rdquo; he said softly to himself between breaths. Ahead of him on the long bridge his dad appeared running. He smiled to himself. The music he was listening to changed to a different track. &ldquo;Sweet Dreams, Ministry of Sound Running Trax Winter 2011&rdquo; appeared at the top of his vision, next to more text … &ldquo;Pace 5:27/km, 20sec slower/km&rdquo;. Memories of his childhood came flooding back of them running together at the park near their home, him desperately trying to keep up with his shorter legs. Better catch the old man now he thought, I&rsquo;m slacking off! He gained on his dad and was finally running in sync with him, side by side.</p>

<p>The nanotechnology in his body connected him to the vast services and data available on the net and seamlessly augmented his reality, which in this case was his vision and hearing. His dad had been born into a time when the world was starting to emerge from their pre-digital caves, and people started leaving digital footprints everywhere they went. He was benefiting from his dads digital footprint now. His dad loved to run, and had recorded them for his own benefit using the primitive tracking technology and services of the time.</p>

<p>This was the first time Liam had been to this city. His dad had been here before and run this same route. As he ran side by side with his dad, listening to the same music he had listened to many years before he felt connected to him, in a way that would not have been possible for his dad&rsquo;s generation. This was his dad, in his prime, doing something that he now loved too, and they were doing it together at different places in time.</p>

<p>As he stopped at the end of the road and looked out over the water, the sight of the Sydney Opera House greeted him. They both stood there, looking at the Opera House, and the Harbour Bridge to the right. He turned his head and looked at the avatar of his dad, and smiled.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-07-25-running-memory/photo-small.jpg" width="770" height="295" title="Photo" >
<a href="/media/images/2013-07-25-running-memory/photo.jpg">Photo (Original)</a></p>

<p><a href="/blog/2013/03/09/glitch-in-the-matrix/">Glitch in the Matrix</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Along the Watchtower]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/06/07/all-along-the-watchtower/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/06/07/all-along-the-watchtower</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He sat on the bus in the pre-dawn light. Fog partially covered the windows. The inside of the bus felt enclosed in a safe bubble type of way with other silent, faceless souls, the backs of their heads illuminated by the smartphones their heads were buried in.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The brief hint of a smile, or maybe sadness touched his face as he thought of the irony, people connected to the world, but isolated from others in their own bubbles. Lights flashed past the windows as the bus ambled along.</p>

<p>As if in a dream, he slowly turned his head and looked out the window. In awe, he watched where the approaching lights silently moved from the clear part of the window to the fogged part, they suddenly transformed, almost spewing their aura outward in a bright halo effect. The fog combined with the escaping darkness seemed to act as a visible screen to their true essence, their souls, which was otherwise obscured.</p>

<p>The bus came to a stop. He was still looking out the fogged part of the window as his eyes focused on what looked like, incredibly, a rider on a horse approaching in the distance. He felt locked in place and unable to move his head to see if the rider would disappear when viewed through the clear part of the window. As the rider got closer his eyes shifted, and he saw another rider on a horse behind. Two riders. The wind began to howl against the side of the bus.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nMNDq7Bz8ug">All Along the Watchtower</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glitch in the Matrix]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/03/09/glitch-in-the-matrix/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/03/09/glitch-in-the-matrix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He sprinted, his powerful legs heaving with the strain of propelling his massive 6 foot 3 inch frame forward. His lungs sucked in as much air as they could in the short span they were allowed. They were gaining on him. Two distinct shapes in the distance. 17.2 meters and closing.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>As he glanced back a few moments before he could just make out their features with the ambient lighting from the houses and dim street lights. Their faces were wolf like, but sinister, hideously contorted. They were howling, but only he could hear it. Long ethereal tormented howls filled his night. His v-band augmented reality display identified them as level 6 ghosts. They were there, but not really there. The two runners were also wearing v-bands, and running in another part of the world. They were chosen by v-net as competitors and spawned on his run.</p>

<p>He chuckled to himself, as to them he appeared as Astro Boy. These young kids had no originality, thinking they could psych older runners. But this was serious. If he let them gain ground he risked his level 7 standing in the league.</p>

<p>&lsquo;Show my last ghost&rsquo; he said out loud while running, seemingly to himself. His previous self spawned in front of him, running his previous run. He could see he was slacking off and the two wolf like ghosts were gaining. He forced his legs to increase his pace, and sucked in more oxygen. He started gaining on his past ghost and pulling away from his pursuers.</p>

<p>Suddenly his vision went black, and then it was back, but instead of the familiar scene in front of him he saw trees densely packed together. He was in a forest. The scene was moving fast, bouncing up and down, left and right. He kept running straight along the path he was on, but couldn&rsquo;t see where he was going. His v-band was showing him someone from somewhere else. What the frak was happening!</p>

<p>All this happened in seconds, so he kept running, confused, and expecting that the v-band would correct itself. The scene from his v-band lurched as if the person fell, and then was facing up looking at the trees and dark sky. The vision started to darken, but before it went completely dark he saw what looked like a primitive hunter standing over him. He looked big, muscly, but with short arms, and was carrying a large spear.</p>

<p><a href="/blog/2013/02/15/running/">Running</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
