<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | Peter Boni]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-22T14:49:56+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.peterboni.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Boni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design: Little Things Matter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/09/22/design-little-things-matter/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-22T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/09/22/design-little-things-matter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like running &amp; listening to music using my iPhone. Up until recently I was using Sennheiser in-ear headphones without a remote or mic. The headphones caused me several problems before I finally decided to buy new headphones, which made me think about design.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The first problem was that even though the Sennheiser headphones were in-ear, they kept falling out, which was really annoying. The second problem was that I couldn&rsquo;t forward tracks. Listening to a slowish song approaching a hill is not inspiring at all. The third problem occurred when I was running, and would get the occasional incoming message. Fumbling to get the iPhone out of my <a href="http://www.spibelt.com.au">SPI Belt</a> &amp; read the message while running (to see if it was urgent) was difficult.</p>

<p>I did a quick review of headphones with remote &amp; mic in the Apple Store and purchased the Sennheiser OCX 685i In-Ear Sports Headphones.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-09-22-design-little-things-matter/IMG_1154.jpg" width="500" height="666" title="Sennheiser OCX 685i In-Ear Sports Headphones" ></p>

<p>The ear clip design, combined with the lightweight cord &amp; clip means that they stay secure while running. No more falling out. The remote &amp; mic work &ndash; I have full control over music. I can use Siri to listen to incoming messages, and dictate a reply. I can even use Siri to <a href="https://twitter.com/peterboni/status/379924494527131649">Tweet</a>. The headphones are also sweat &amp; water resistant. Nearly perfect.</p>

<blockquote><p>The only problem I have with them is the <em>design</em> of the remote, which detracts from the overall experience of using the product.</p></blockquote>

<p>Compare the design of the remote on the Sennheiser in the above picture to the remote on the Apple EarPods in the below picture.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-09-22-design-little-things-matter/IMG_1155.jpg" width="500" height="666" title="Apple EarPods with Remote and Mic" ></p>

<p>Can you guess what the problem is? When I&rsquo;m running &amp; listening to music, I&rsquo;m watching the road ahead. I move my hand &amp; fingers to the remote near my neck, grab it, and feel the controls. They&rsquo;re all placed together &amp; feel like they blend into each other. It feels like one button. This is the exact opposite experience on the Apple EarPods, where because of the clear indent in the middle of the remote I feel immediately by touch how to activate the different functions that the 3 buttons enable.</p>

<p>I was reading this article today &ndash; <a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-09-20/apple-ceo-tim-cooks-complete-interview-with-bloomberg-businessweek">Tim Cook: The Complete Interview</a>, and there are a few really good quotes from Tim Cook that I think are relevant.</p>

<blockquote><p>&lsquo;We’re a product company, and so the products show the values of a company. They speak to innovation. They speak to caring about every detail. They’re a reminder of how incredibly important experience is &hellip; every detail has been thought through. The experience is an “Aha” moment.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>And then this one.</p>

<blockquote><p>&lsquo;Nobody worries about buttons and finishes. Nobody really worries about the experience, and we do. We’re really proud that we do.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Design is important, and only going to become more so &ndash; <a href="http://www.fastcodesign.com/3017485/the-3-future-waves-in-design-and-how-to-ride-them">The 3 Future Waves In Design, And How To Ride Them</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
