<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Surreal | Peter Boni]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/categories/surreal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-10T12:32:25+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.peterboni.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Boni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glitch in the Matrix]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/03/09/glitch-in-the-matrix/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/03/09/glitch-in-the-matrix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He sprinted, his powerful legs heaving with the strain of propelling his massive 6 foot 3 inch frame forward. His lungs sucked in as much air as they could in the short span they were allowed. They were gaining on him. Two distinct shapes in the distance. 17.2 meters &amp; closing.</p>

<p>As he glanced back a few moments before he could just make out their features with the ambient lighting from the houses &amp; dim street lights. Their faces were wolf like, but sinister, hideously contorted. They were howling, but only he could hear it. Long ethereal tormented howls filled his night. His v-band augmented reality display identified them as level 6 ghosts. They were there, but not really there. The two runners were also wearing v-bands, and running in another part of the world. They were chosen by v-net as competitors and spawned on his run.</p>

<p>He chuckled to himself, as to them he appeared as Astro Boy. These young kids had no originality, thinking they could psych older runners. But this was serious. If he let them gain ground he risked his level 7 standing in the league.</p>

<p>'Show my last ghost' he said out loud while running, seemingly to himself. His previous self spawned in front of him, running his previous run. He could see he was slacking off &amp; the two wolf like ghosts were gaining. He forced his legs to increase his pace, and sucked in more oxygen. He started gaining on his past ghost &amp; pulling away from his pursuers.</p>

<p>Suddenly his vision went black, and then it was back, but instead of the familiar scene in front of him he saw trees densely packed together. He was in a forest. The scene was moving fast, bouncing up and down, left and right. He kept running straight along the path he was on, but couldn't see where he was going. His v-band was showing him someone from somewhere else. What the frak was happening!</p>

<p>All this happened in seconds, so he kept running, confused, and expecting that the v-band would correct itself. The scene from his v-band lurched as if the person fell, and then was facing up looking at the trees &amp; dark sky. The vision started to darken, but before it went completely dark he saw what looked like a primitive hunter standing over him. He looked big, muscly, but with short arms, and was carrying a large spear.</p>

<p><a href="/blog/2013/02/15/running/">Running</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/15/running/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/02/15/running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>He was running. <em>Hard.</em> He knew instinctively to the very fibre of his being why he was running. Survival. His life. If he didn't run, and run fast, he was dead.</p>

<p>They were after him, howling for blood, and a more primal drive, the thrill of the hunt, and the kill. He was the prey.</p>

<p>His hunters were larger than him, bigger boned, with barrel chests, shorter arms &amp; legs, but more powerful. They carried more primitive heavy stabbing spears compared to his more versatile throwing spear, which meant they needed to get close to him.</p>

<p>He knew they were getting closer. The sounds of their heavy footfalls rang through the dense forest. Their garbled grunts &amp; taunts echoed all around him, their purpose to intimidate, to frighten, but they caused the opposite reaction, it triggered his survival instinct. He ran faster.</p>

<p>Suddenly he tripped over a branch, and fell hard hitting his head on a rock. As his vision darkened, he felt like he was being thrown through something strange. And then there was total darkness. An enveloped feeling. No sound. No predators. And then, again, strangely, but differently ...</p>

<p>He was running. Steadily. Consistently. Really concentrating on his breathing, his stride, the way his feet hit the ground, and his overall rhythm. He was running for fitness, competing against imagined binary ghosts, some of other souls - thousands of them scattered around the planet, but also some of himself at different places in time, but in his mind mostly against ones from the past.</p>

<p>His mind created the purpose &amp; the urgency for his running. The small computing device attached to his body was capable of storing &amp; processing massive amounts of data. While he ran it was working to pump high beats per minute music to his ears which when combined with his brain increased his heart rate &amp; blood flow.</p>

<p>The small computing device was also working to receive signals being broadcast from an array of satellites orbiting the planet, to triangulate his exact location on the planet every second. It then sent this information back into the airwaves, to be captured by a vast array of computing devices &amp; software, which then stored &amp; analysed the information, and sent back statistics &amp; insights that he could analyse, share, and interact with later.</p>

<p>He looked ahead as he ran at the scenery slowly bobbing up &amp; down, up &amp; down. He pulled more air into his lungs. This was different. Strange. Somewhat lonely, but not. He couldn't figure out why, but it felt good to run.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
