<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Peter Boni]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-15T16:32:03+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.peterboni.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Boni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Numbers]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/01/01/running-numbers/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-01T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2014/01/01/running-numbers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In January 2013 I wanted to try something different, and decided to try running as
I had never been a runner.
In February I wrote a short story called Running, and then went on to
write a few more blog posts during the year related to <a href="/blog/categories/running/">Running</a>.</p>

<p>While I was doing all this writing, I ran a total of 529.3 kilometers,
for 53 hours, and burned 51,578 calories, which is about 25 days worth of
food for an adult (based on 2,000 calories a day).</p>

<!--more-->


<p>At the beginning of the year I could barely run 2.5 kilometers, in 6 minutes,
42 seconds per kilometer.</p>

<p>By the end of the year I had run in the City to Surf 12 kilometers (I finished in
1 hour, 14 minutes, 1 second), and finished the year strong with an arbitrary
goal &ndash; run 5 kilometers every day for 5 days.
I had also run 2.8 kilometers in 4 minutes, 39 seconds per kilometer.</p>

<p>I also lost 12.8 kilograms.</p>

<p>This year I plan to train &amp; run in the City to Surf Half Marathon, which
<a href="https://www.google.com/#q=half+marathon">according to Google</a> is 21.097494 kilometers.
Very precise, thanks Google.</p>

<p>As I look back at last year it&rsquo;s the experience of running (and writing about it) that
I loved, and it&rsquo;s why I kept doing it. It&rsquo;s not about the numbers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cylon Style: A short funny lesson about differences]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/10/19/cylon-style/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-19T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/10/19/cylon-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I received a message on May 7, 2013 that turned into a short lesson about differences, with a rather funny ending. I saved a photo of the conversation and still think about it even now.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First, some background. This person has the soul of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cylon_(Battlestar_Galactica)">Cylon</a>. Not one of the new humanoid models, but one of the early toaster models. He&rsquo;s quietly confident and communicates with the minimum amount of words available in our language to convey meaning.</p>

<p>The incoming message simply read &lsquo;you got 10 minutes for a chat tonight ?&rsquo;. Immediately I smiled as the message was all lowercase. To me it&rsquo;s kind of like people on LinkedIn using all lowercase for their <em>name</em>. Yes, they do exist.</p>

<p>I replied asking if it could wait until tomorrow. The reply was one word, all lowercase &ndash; &lsquo;can&rsquo;. At this point I was amused enough to make fun of him. I replied &lsquo;Like I said &hellip; war-era Centurion model Cylon&rsquo;. The reply came back, once again one word, all lowercase &ndash; &lsquo;efficiency&rsquo;.</p>

<p>I thought about this for a moment. We were communicating but the replies weren&rsquo;t what I expected, i.e. a few well constructed words or sentences. I shot back &lsquo;Where&rsquo;s the passion or love in efficiency?&rsquo;. The reply came and I laughed out loud &ndash; &lsquo;it&rsquo;s in there cylon style&rsquo;.</p>

<p>Touché Cylon.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-10-19-cylon-style/photo.png" width="320" height="582" title="Cylon Style" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iHealth Renaissance: Change Your Body & Mind One App at a Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/10/01/ihealth-renaissance/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-01T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/10/01/ihealth-renaissance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-10-01-ihealth-renaissance/img_1181.jpg" width="640" height="365" title="iHealth" ></p>

<p>I have experienced a personal health renaissance over the last year. My iPhone<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> is teaching me how to change my health, both body &amp; mind. It has offered motivation when I needed it. I believe that the iHealth Renaissance is just getting started. It could do the same for you if you let it. Let me explain how.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It all started innocently enough on January 1, 2013 when I installed the first health app on my iPhone &ndash; RunKeeper, that I had heard about from a friend. I didn&rsquo;t think I was <em>that</em> unfit as I cycled regularly, and was able to do 80km rides at a decent pace. I wanted to try something different, and decided to try running as I had never been a runner. I actually didn&rsquo;t like it as I thought that I couldn&rsquo;t do it &ndash; that I wasn&rsquo;t built for it. I&rsquo;m 189 cm (6 feet 2.4 inches), and was about 98 kg. Overweight for sure, but at the time not really concerned about it. My first run was the day after, January 2 when I ran 2.55 km at a pace of 6:42 per km, on a completely flat course.</p>

<p>RunKeeper gave me all sorts of rich feedback. Realtime audio feedback on my run. Visual statistics after my run &amp; of all previous runs. I could easily hear, see &amp; track my progress. The social networking that was built in took the feedback to the next level. Likes &amp; comments on my runs, as well as being able to view friends runs, combined with the leaderboard, gave me more motivation. I was really <a href="/blog/categories/running/">enjoying running</a>. I wasn&rsquo;t conscious of why I kept coming back &amp; using RunKeeper until I experienced a talk from <a href="http://drjasonfox.com/">Dr Jason Fox</a> (a &lsquo;motivation strategy &amp; design expert&rsquo;) at a technology conference later in the year.</p>

<blockquote><p>RunKeeper had designed running to be inherently motivating. It reduced the latency between the effort &amp; feedback. It enhanced the visibility of, and gave me a clear sense of progress. The more visible my progress, the more motivated I became. The more I ran.</p></blockquote>

<p>After RunKeeper came Strava for my cycling. I think RunKeeper supported cycling as a different activity type but I knew friends using Strava for cycling. If you were around and using the Internet in the late 90s you will remember ICQ starting the IM (Instant Messaging) wars. Some friends were on RunKeeper, and some were on Strava. I was stuck with both, which really means three apps, as Strava has two &ndash; one for cycling and one for running. All this cardio meant that weights were next. Thoughts of figuring out how to do the exercises properly again, and setting up &amp; recording scheduled routines did not motivate me at all. That&rsquo;s when a friend put me on to GymGoal 2 which managed it all for me, and gave me visual help &amp; feedback.</p>

<p>With 4 fitness apps installed &amp; being used regularly next came changing what I put into my body. My wife installed &amp; started using MyNetDiary which is essentially calorie counting, with once again, plenty of feedback that gave me a sense of progress. I could visually see how many calories I was consuming against how many I should consume to meet my target weight. What it did more than that though was teach me about what I was eating. I was shocked at a few things, for example almonds &hellip; holy crap! It hasn&rsquo;t changed what I eat, as I still enjoy beer &amp; chocolate, but it has changed my behaviour. I now think about the quality &amp; quantity of what I will put into my body.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-10-01-ihealth-renaissance/img_1137.jpg" width="500" height="500" title="Breakfast" ></p>

<p>With 5 health apps installed &amp; being used regularly I started seeing changes. 8 months of running, and 1.5 months of changing the way I eat I had dropped over 8 kg in weight, and could now comfortably run 5 km at a pace of 5:30 per km, with nice steep hills thrown in.</p>

<p>There are two more health apps that I have installed &amp; started using. The first one I came across when I read an article <a href="http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/05/09/the-scientific-7-minute-workout/">The Scientific 7-Minute Workout</a>. I thought that it would come in handy when I was short on time, and also as a good way to shake things up. Check out the &lsquo;7 Minute Workout &ldquo;Seven&rdquo;&rsquo; app. The last one I came across when I read a Lifehacker article <a href="http://lifehacker.com/what-happens-to-the-brain-when-you-meditate-and-how-it-1202533314">What Happens to the Brain When You Meditate (And How it Benefits You)</a>, that recommended an app created by a former Buddhist monk called <a href="http://www.getsomeheadspace.com/">Headspace</a>. Check out the app &lsquo;Headspace&rsquo;, it&rsquo;s meditation when &amp; where you have the time, which for me is on my way to work on the bus. I&rsquo;m really excited about giving meditation a go, and Headspace was built for the iHealth Renaissance.</p>

<p>I now have 7 health apps installed &amp; being used, which is the majority category of apps that I use on my iPhone. I haven&rsquo;t used a Nike+ Fuelband, Jawbone UP, or a Fitbit Flex, but I can see that the iHealth Renaissance is just starting, and that these are just early wearable accessory products.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s frustrating that I need multiple apps for the same thing, and also that I need to enter the same information into different apps. For example most of the health apps want to know my gender, age, height &amp; weight, to be able to provide me meaningful feedback. Why do I need to provide my data multiple times?</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s interesting looking at the move Apple has made with the iPhone 5s, by introducing a motion coprocessor called the M7, which continuously measures motion data &amp; makes it available for apps. I can&rsquo;t wait for the next generation of iHealth apps &amp; wearable accessory products. I think we still need wearable accessory products as apps are tucked away nicely on your iPhone. You choose when to interact with them. We need devices that we can see that constantly motivate us. Devices that further reduce the latency between effort &amp; feedback in an effortless, visual, motivational way. I think that these devices will still be accessory products that augment the core richer connected experience that can be delivered via your iPhone.</p>

<p>So the iHealth Renaissance is making good progress, but where is the iWealth Renaissance? The current batch of mobile apps from the financial services industry are primarily sales &amp; service based. Buy this product. View &amp; manage your accounts. They haven&rsquo;t started to take the next step.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>I use an iPhone. I use the term iPhone in this article to mean smartphone, or what I think of as a native Internet mobile personal assistant &amp; augmentation device.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Communication]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/09/01/communication/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-01T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/09/01/communication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There has probably been millions of words written about communication. So why bother?
We communicate every day, but most of us take it for granted.
We think we know how to do it, but do we really consider the massive impact it has on
our lives? Do we actively try to get better at it?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I vividly remember my daughter around the age of 3 when learning to express
herself would suddenly blurt out &lsquo;I don&rsquo;t like it&rsquo;, or &lsquo;That makes me sad&rsquo;.
I remember feeling proud, but at the same time flustered, and sometimes annoyed
because of the timing. She was doing what my wife (an infinitely better communicator
than me) had taught her to do, to vocalise her feelings without thinking, just throw
them out there. Before she learnt to do this she used to get frustrated &amp; express
her feelings in other ways, the most common of which was crying.</p>

<p>So if expressing your feelings &amp; thoughts effectively is one part of communication the other part is what comes back to you once you do this, and what you do with it.
My daughter is 5 &frac12; now, and can engage in meaningful communication, interspersed with
periods of her imagination taking control. I notice that when I say something to her,
she will pause, and then immediately respond with a question, or less frequently an
interesting factoid that she draws out from her limited experience.
She does this with an openness that I find refreshing &amp; disarming.
Her words, tone, and body language are all aligned with a genuine interest.
There&rsquo;s not a shred of guile.</p>

<p>Of course as adults we all know how much more complex it gets. There are far more
less effective ways to communicate than in person. I wish I could convey to you how
much I dislike email &amp; it&rsquo;s seductive call, but alas, I&rsquo;m still learning.</p>

<p>I have this surreal mental movie of us all as adults. We&rsquo;re walking around in a shared existence, but within our own bubbles of reality. We have goggles strapped to our heads that we can&rsquo;t take off. These goggles are much like camera lenses that can have multiple filters stacked on. The goggles protect our eyes, but they also filter our vision. As we grow our eyes change but then so too do the goggles, as filters are added, changed, or removed. I wonder what would happen if we were to regularly pause and consider what we are, and how we communicate with those around us.</p>

<p>There has probably been millions of words written about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication">communication</a>. So why bother? Because I&rsquo;m actively trying to get better at it.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-09-01-communication/photo-small.jpg" width="700" height="467" title="Photo" >
<a href="/media/images/2013-09-01-communication/photo.jpg">Photo (Original)</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Is Water]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/05/11/this-is-water/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-11T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/05/11/this-is-water</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently took a month leave from work &amp; did absolutely nothing. Well not nothing. I did something I&rsquo;ve never done before. I didn&rsquo;t do any work. I spent it with my family. I relaxed. Really relaxed. I disconnected from my life of work, more work, the Internet, computers &amp; technology. Well, ok, mostly for the last few. This may not seem momentous to you, but for me it was.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The last major break I had was when my son Liam was born. My idea then of relaxing in between all the crying and sleepless nights was to learn the Android platform by creating an <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=au.com.bankwest.mobile&amp;hl=en">App</a>. The App was released August 2011. Now with an average rating of 3.8 out of 5 and over 80,000 installs it has been successful, even if I wasn&rsquo;t successful at relaxing.</p>

<p>When I returned to work I felt strange. The first few days I was wondering why I was there. What was I doing. What was my purpose. Why did I come here (other than the obvious reasons). I&rsquo;d look out the window and feel in my soul that I needed to return to the existence I had come from. I missed my pain in the butt kids. There was the usual jokes with family and friends. &ldquo;Hey, how&rsquo;s reality? Happy to be back at work? ;)&rdquo;, to which I replied jokingly &ldquo;Reality sucks!&rdquo;.</p>

<p>What I started to notice in the first few days was that I was relaxed at my core. I could think before speaking &amp; putting words out there, making sure they were positive and added value. It sharpened my focus. I no longer felt like a speeding train. I felt like I&rsquo;d slowed down inside, and was more effective for it.</p>

<p>A few more days passed, and it was the end of the first week. The feeling of strangeness was still there, but so too was the feeling of being relaxed at my core. I resolved to fight like hell to keep it. I started to change my habits. I made time for breakfast in the morning. I resolved not to rush. I made time for exercise; riding, running, walking &amp; started weights again after many years. I made time for my family. I made time for meditation. I&rsquo;ve made time for thinking, writing &amp; doing. There&rsquo;s only so many hours in a day, so I stopped doing things that didn&rsquo;t add value, and just added noise to my life. It&rsquo;s a liberating feeling.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s affected me in other ways too. I had one of my best runs in my first week back at work. Relaxed. Smooth. Good pace &amp; rhythm. But still competitive. I still increased my pace, clawing at the road, gasping for breath for the last couple hundred metres. A neighbour would have seen this person run up the road, collapse on the lawn, gasping for breath, scrambling at his iPhone to press finish on Strava. As I lay there on the lawn, the beats from the earbuds combining with the pounding of my ears, sweat pouring off my face and down my neck, the wind hitting me, I felt alive. I felt great. It&rsquo;s reflected in my edited Strava Name for the run &ndash; &ldquo;BOOM FEEL MY RYTHM STICK BOUNCE !&rdquo;.</p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/65576562">This Is Water</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
