<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Peter Boni]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-22T17:18:44+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.peterboni.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Peter Boni]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Communication]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/09/01/communication/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-01T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/09/01/communication</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There has probably been millions of words written about communication. So why bother?
We communicate every day, but most of us take it for granted.
We think we know how to do it, but do we really consider the massive impact it has on
our lives? Do we actively try to get better at it?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I vividly remember my daughter around the age of 3 when learning to express
herself would suddenly blurt out &lsquo;I don&rsquo;t like it&rsquo;, or &lsquo;That makes me sad&rsquo;.
I remember feeling proud, but at the same time flustered, and sometimes annoyed
because of the timing. She was doing what my wife (an infinitely better communicator
than me) had taught her to do, to vocalise her feelings without thinking, just throw
them out there. Before she learnt to do this she used to get frustrated &amp; express
her feelings in other ways, the most common of which was crying.</p>

<p>So if expressing your feelings &amp; thoughts effectively is one part of communication the other part is what comes back to you once you do this, and what you do with it.
My daughter is 5 &frac12; now, and can engage in meaningful communication, interspersed with
periods of her imagination taking control. I notice that when I say something to her,
she will pause, and then immediately respond with a question, or less frequently an
interesting factoid that she draws out from her limited experience.
She does this with an openness that I find refreshing &amp; disarming.
Her words, tone, and body language are all aligned with a genuine interest.
There&rsquo;s not a shred of guile.</p>

<p>Of course as adults we all know how much more complex it gets. There are far more
less effective ways to communicate than in person. I wish I could convey to you how
much I dislike email &amp; it&rsquo;s seductive call, but alas, I&rsquo;m still learning.</p>

<p>I have this surreal mental movie of us all as adults. We&rsquo;re walking around in a shared existence, but within our own bubbles of reality. We have goggles strapped to our heads that we can&rsquo;t take off. These goggles are much like camera lenses that can have multiple filters stacked on. The goggles protect our eyes, but they also filter our vision. As we grow our eyes change but then so too do the goggles, as filters are added, changed, or removed. I wonder what would happen if we were to regularly pause and consider what we are, and how we communicate with those around us.</p>

<p>There has probably been millions of words written about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication">communication</a>. So why bother? Because I&rsquo;m actively trying to get better at it.</p>

<p><img class="fancybox center" src="/media/images/2013-09-01-communication/photo-small.jpg" width="700" height="467" title="Photo" >
<a href="/media/images/2013-09-01-communication/photo.jpg">Photo (Original)</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Is Water]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/05/11/this-is-water/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-11T07:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.peterboni.net/blog/2013/05/11/this-is-water</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently took a month leave from work &amp; did absolutely nothing. Well not nothing. I did something I&rsquo;ve never done before. I didn&rsquo;t do any work. I spent it with my family. I relaxed. Really relaxed. I disconnected from my life of work, more work, the Internet, computers &amp; technology. Well, ok, mostly for the last few. This may not seem momentous to you, but for me it was.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The last major break I had was when my son Liam was born. My idea then of relaxing in between all the crying and sleepless nights was to learn the Android platform by creating an <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=au.com.bankwest.mobile&amp;hl=en">App</a>. The App was released August 2011. Now with an average rating of 3.8 out of 5 and over 80,000 installs it has been successful, even if I wasn&rsquo;t successful at relaxing.</p>

<p>When I returned to work I felt strange. The first few days I was wondering why I was there. What was I doing. What was my purpose. Why did I come here (other than the obvious reasons). I&rsquo;d look out the window and feel in my soul that I needed to return to the existence I had come from. I missed my pain in the butt kids. There was the usual jokes with family and friends. &ldquo;Hey, how&rsquo;s reality? Happy to be back at work? ;)&rdquo;, to which I replied jokingly &ldquo;Reality sucks!&rdquo;.</p>

<p>What I started to notice in the first few days was that I was relaxed at my core. I could think before speaking &amp; putting words out there, making sure they were positive and added value. It sharpened my focus. I no longer felt like a speeding train. I felt like I&rsquo;d slowed down inside, and was more effective for it.</p>

<p>A few more days passed, and it was the end of the first week. The feeling of strangeness was still there, but so too was the feeling of being relaxed at my core. I resolved to fight like hell to keep it. I started to change my habits. I made time for breakfast in the morning. I resolved not to rush. I made time for exercise; riding, running, walking &amp; started weights again after many years. I made time for my family. I made time for meditation. I&rsquo;ve made time for thinking, writing &amp; doing. There&rsquo;s only so many hours in a day, so I stopped doing things that didn&rsquo;t add value, and just added noise to my life. It&rsquo;s a liberating feeling.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s affected me in other ways too. I had one of my best runs in my first week back at work. Relaxed. Smooth. Good pace &amp; rhythm. But still competitive. I still increased my pace, clawing at the road, gasping for breath for the last couple hundred metres. A neighbour would have seen this person run up the road, collapse on the lawn, gasping for breath, scrambling at his iPhone to press finish on Strava. As I lay there on the lawn, the beats from the earbuds combining with the pounding of my ears, sweat pouring off my face and down my neck, the wind hitting me, I felt alive. I felt great. It&rsquo;s reflected in my edited Strava Name for the run &ndash; &ldquo;BOOM FEEL MY RYTHM STICK BOUNCE !&rdquo;.</p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/65576562">This Is Water</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
